TEJASWI REDDY (Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in APIGEE API management, Software Development, Software Architecture, IT Project Management, Software Design, Requirement Gathering, Bamboo, Splunk, GitHub, Azure Devops



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Value Labs Solutions Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: APIGEE, API, Senior Software Engineer, REST API, AZURE Devops, Splunk, Github, postman, CICD

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

4 years of overall experience as Software Engineer.

3.8 years of relevant experience on API development and management.

Worked on creating Apigee Proxies, developer apps, products and KVM operations.

Worked on creating Swagger specs that specify open API specifications.

Worked on API monitoring tool Splunk to check logs of Apigee proxies.

Worked on Azure DevOps to achieve CICD approach to deploy proxies between environments

Implemented Oauth mechanism (Apigee Proxy) to give access token to third party application to login to the application.

Worked on Spring Boot Micro services and Restful based web services to interact with

different application.

Worked on Dynamo DB and Redis Amazon Webservices

Implemented Bamboo scripts for Applications

Worked on ETL tools like Snaplogic & MFT

A direct Client Interaction for several meetings such as fortnight application status

meeting and as PVT support for upstream/downstream applications.

Work Experience

Value Labs Solutions as Senior Software Engineer Dec 2019 to Till Date

Experienced APIGEE developer along with knowledge of Devops tools

Wipro as Project Engineer Jun 2019 to Nov 2019

Worked as APIGEE developer

Infosys Pvt Ltd as APIGEE developer

Aug 2016 to Jun 2019

Job Profile: Worked as a Software Engineer and supported for Apigee Aka API developmentProject 1: SVC Selfcare Outages Type: Web Based Application Client: Telstra Duration: 10 Months

Description: This project aims to build a middleware system which retrieves the outage details from both Telstra & NBN Co backend services and provide to end consumer systems based on NBN AVC Id, ADSL FNN, Bigpond Email and Cable MAC address.

Responsibilities/Achievements:

Participating project planning sessions with business analysts and team Primary offshore Apigee developer for the application. Performed several deployments on Non-Production and Production servers. Used JavaScript for validation. Created Web Services using Java and JavaScript Developed gueries to Extract data from database Responsible for Unit Testing Policies Using postman Creation/Modification of code as per new stories in the scrum.

Environment: Java, JavaScript, STS, SOAP UI, REST, GIT, Apigee

Role: Software Engineer

Project 2: 4GFW Type: Web Based Application Client: Telstra Duration: 9 Months

Description: 4GFW project aims is to keep customers informed about the outage events affecting their service. End users / systems can subscribe for the outages and outage API / Customer Service Impact API will update the users about the status changes, instead of consumer systems need to poll for outages and identify changes made in outage events.

Responsibilities/Achievements:

Developed Proxies, Products and Developer Apps. Interacted with team lead and Testers to resolve the bugs. Reporting daily work status to management. Handled large number of application related dockets. Also worked on several Problem dockets (PBI). Implemented Bamboo Deployment Tool for deploying Micro services into PCF (Pivotal Cloud Foundry). Storing the Downstream data into AWS Dynamo DB and Redis Services

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from KSR Institute of Technology and Sciences, affiliated by JNTUK in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
API Production		2020	3 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
Apigee		2020	3 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
Apigee API management		2020	3 Year(s) 7 Month(s)
Dynamo DB, Redis Cache		2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Bamboo, Pivotal CLoud Foundry		2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Bambi Splunk, Pivotal Tracker,		2019	2 Year(s) 10 Month(s)
POSTMAN REST Client		2020	3 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
GitHub		2020	3 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Projects

Project Title: SAPB1 To offer Integrations

Client: IKEA

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 4

Skill Used: APIGEE, splunk, GitHub, Azure Devops

Role Description: APIGEE developer

Project Details: This project aims in handling requests from SAPB1 to Offer management

Project Title: Offer To SAPB1 Integrations

Client: IKEA

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2020 - May 2020 Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 4

Skill Used: APIGEE, Snaplogic, GitHub, Azure Devops, Splunk Role Description: APIGEE developer and Snaplogic integrator

Project Details: This project involves in handling the requests coming from a System called Onsweb/ Offer management which posts transaction data like goods issue, goods receipt, sales delivery, purchase orders, paper stock, etc to the system SAPB1. APIGEE acts as trigger which will receive data from offer and post it to SAPB1 by following security mechanisms.

Project Title: Y-receipts

Client: KAO

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2019 - Oct 2019 Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 2

Skill Used: APIGEE, GitHub

Role Description: APIGEE DEVELOPER

Project Details: Integration between OVC backend and yreceipts

Project Title: Autonomous CT Dashboard

Client: Telstra

Duration: Jun 2018 - Feb 2019 Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 12 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Spring Boot, Microservices, GIT, Bamboo, PCF

Role Description: Programmer

Project Details: This project aims to provide solutions to the technicians in the delay of issue

Project Title: 4GFW Client: Telstra

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2017 - May 2018

Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Other Team Size: 12

Skill Used: APIGEE, BAMBOO, GIT, PCF Role Description: APIGEE DEVELOPER

Project Details: 4GFW project aims is to keep customers informed about the outage events

Project Title: Selfcare Outages

Client: Telstra

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2016 - Aug 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bangalore

Role: Other Team Size: 12

Skill Used: APIGEE, GIT, BAMBOO, PCF Role Description: APIGEE DEVELOPER

Project Details: This project aims to retrieve outage information from backend services and forward to the customers with

desired changes.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time